[
  {
    "no": "01",
    "question": "What is Python?",
    "options": [
      "A high-level programming language",
      "A type of snake",
      "A database management system",
      "A web browser"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "A high-level programming language"
  },
  {
    "no": "02",
    "question": "Which symbol is used for comments in Python?",
    "options": ["//", "#", "--", "/* */"],
    "correctAnswer": "#"
  },
  {
    "no": "03",
    "question": "What is the purpose of 'if' statement in Python?",
    "options": [
      "To define a function",
      "To loop over a sequence",
      "To execute code conditionally",
      "To import modules"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "To execute code conditionally"
  },
  {
    "no": "04",
    "question": "Which data type is mutable in Python?",
    "options": ["List", "Tuple", "String", "Set"],
    "correctAnswer": "List"
  },
  {
    "no": "05",
    "question": "What is the purpose of 'len()' function in Python?",
    "options": [
      "To remove an item from a list",
      "To calculate the length of a string",
      "To convert a string to uppercase",
      "To generate a list of numbers"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "To calculate the length of a string"
  },
  {
    "no": "06",
    "question": "What does 'import random' do in Python?",
    "options": [
      "It imports the random module for generating random numbers",
      "It imports the math module for mathematical operations",
      "It imports the time module for working with time-related functions",
      "It imports the os module for interacting with the operating system"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "It imports the random module for generating random numbers"
  },
  {
    "no": "07",
    "question": "What does 'lambda' function do in Python?",
    "options": [
      "Defines a named function",
      "Creates an anonymous function",
      "Generates a list of numbers",
      "Performs list comprehension"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Creates an anonymous function"
  },
  {
    "no": "08",
    "question": "What is the purpose of 'zip()' function in Python?",
    "options": [
      "To compress files",
      "To zip two lists together",
      "To unzip files",
      "To calculate the sum of elements in a list"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "To zip two lists together"
  },
  {
    "no": "09",
    "question": "What is the correct syntax to open a file in Python?",
    "options": [
      "file = open('filename.txt')",
      "open('filename.txt', 'r')",
      "file.open('filename.txt')",
      "open.file('filename.txt')"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "open('filename.txt', 'r')"
  },
  {
    "no": "10",
    "question": "What is the purpose of 'range()' function in Python?",
    "options": [
      "To generate a range of numbers",
      "To calculate the factorial of a number",
      "To perform mathematical operations",
      "To define a range for looping"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "To generate a range of numbers"
  }
]
